Guide to the Robert Fridenberg Collection of Portrait and Topographical Prints
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Portraits, Series I
  - R
    - Russell, Rachel, Lady, 1636-1723 (Box 171, Folder 2915)
    - Russell, William, Lord, 1639-1683 (Box 171, Folder 2916)
    - Rutland (Box 171, Folder 2917)
    - Rutland, Mary Isabella Manners, Duchess of, 1756-1831 (Box 171, Folder 2918)
    - Rutledge, Edward, 1749-1800 (Box 171, Folder 2919)
    - Ruyter, Michiel Adriaanszoon de, 1607-1676 (Box 171, Folder 2920)
    - Oversize
      - Ra - Ri general, 16 (Box 172 (Oversize), Folder 2921-2936)
      - Ro - Rz general, 11 (Box 173 (Oversize), Folder 2937-2947)
      - Rabelais - Rivington, 26 (Box 174 (Oversize), Folder 2948-2973)
      - Robertson - Ruyter, 25 (Box 175 (Oversize), Folder 2974-2998)
  - S
    - Sa - Scho general, 11 (Box 176, Folder 2999-3009)
    - Schu - Sk general, 15 (Box 177, Folder 3010-3024)
    - Sl - Sta general, 12 (Box 178, Folder 3025-3036)
    - Ste - Sz general, 12 (Box 179, Folder 3037-3048)
    - Sackville, George Germain, Viscount, 1716-1785 (Box 180, Folder 3049)
    - Saint-Evremond, 1613-1703 (Box 180, Folder 3050)
    - Saint-Just, 1767-1794 (Box 180, Folder 3051)
    - Saint-Pierre, Bernardin de, 1737-1814 (Box 180, Folder 3052)
    - Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvroy, duc de, 1675-1755 (Box 180, Folder 3053)
    - Sainte-Marthe, Scévole de, 1536-1623 (Box 180, Folder 3054)
    - Salisbury, Robert Cecil, Earl of, 1563-1612 (Box 180, Folder 3055)
    - Salisbury, Robert Cecil, Marquess of, 1830-1903 (Box 180, Folder 3056)
    - Sand, George, 1804-1876 (Box 180, Folder 3057)
    - Sandeau, Jules, 1811-1883 (Box 180, Folder 3058)
    - Sandwich, Edward Montagu, Earl of, 1625-1672 (Box 180, Folder 3059)
    - Sarasin, Jean-François, 1615-1654 (Box 180, Folder 3060)
    - Sardou, Victorien, 1831-1908 (Box 180, Folder 3061)
    - Sarpi, Paolo, 1552-1623 (Box 180, Folder 3062)
    - Savage, Edward, 1761-1817
    - Savonarola, Girolamo, 1452-1498 (Box 180, Folder 3063)
    - Saxe, Maurice, comte de, 1696-1750 (Box 180, Folder 3064)
    - Saye and Sele, William Fiennes, Viscount, 1582-1662 (Box 180, Folder 3065)
    - Scaliger, Joseph Juste, 1540-1609 (Box 180, Folder 3066)
    - Scanderbeg, 1405?-1468 (Box 180, Folder 3067)
    - Scarron, Monsieur, 1610-1660 (Box 180, Folder 3068)
    - Schill, Ferdinand von, 1776-1809 (Box 180, Folder 3069)
    - Schlegel, August Wilhelm von, 1767-1845 (Box 180, Folder 3070)
    - Schomberg, Charles de, 1601-1656 (Box 180, Folder 3071)
    - Schomberg, Friedrich Hermann Schomberg, Duke of, 1615-1690 (Box 180, Folder 3072)
    - Schwarzenberg, Karl Philipp, Fürst zu, 1771-1820 (Box 180, Folder 3073)
    - Scott, Walter, 1771-1832 (Box 180, Folder 3074)
    - Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866 (Box 180, Folder 3075)
    - Scudéry, M. de (Georges), 1601-1667 (Box 181, Folder 3076)
    - Scudéry, Madeleine de, 1607-1701 (Box 181, Folder 3077)
    - Sébastiani, Horace François Bastien, comte de la Porta, 1772-1851 (Box 181, Folder 3078)
    - Segrais, Jean Regnauld de, 1624-1701 (Box 181, Folder 3079)
    - Séguier, Pierre, 1588-1672 (Box 181, Folder 3080)
    - Ségur, Louis-Philippe, comte de, 1753-1830 (Box 181, Folder 3081)
    - Ségur, Philippe-Henri, marquis de, 1724-1801 (Box 181, Folder 3082)
    - Selden, John, 1584-1654 (Box 181, Folder 3083)
    - Sévigné (Box 181, Folder 3084)
    - Sévigné, Marie de Rabutin-Chantal, marquise de, 1626-1696 (Box 181, Folder 3085)
    - Seymour, Thomas Seymour, Baron, 1508?-1549 (Box 181, Folder 3086)
    - Shaftesbury, Anthony Ashley Cooper, Earl of, 1621-1683 (Box 181, Folder 3087)
    - Shaftesbury, Anthony Ashley Cooper, Earl of, 1801-1885 (Box 181, Folder 3088)
    - Sharp, Granville, 1735-1813 (Box 181, Folder 3089)
    - Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891 (Box 181, Folder 3090)
    - Shirley, James, 1596-1666 (Box 181, Folder 3091)
    - Shrewsbury (Box 181, Folder 3092)
    - Sidney, Algernon, 1622-1683 (Box 181, Folder 3093)
    - Sidney, Philip, Sir, 1554-1586 (Box 181, Folder 3094)
    - Sieyès, Emmanuel Joseph, comte, 1748-1836 (Box 181, Folder 3095)
    - Smith (Box 181, Folder 3096)
    - Smith, Albert, 1816-1860 (Box 181, Folder 3097)
    - Smith, James, 1775-1839 (Box 181, Folder 3098)
    - Smith, O., 1786-1855 (Box 181, Folder 3099)
    - Smith, Sydney, 1771-1845 (Box 181, Folder 3100)
    - Smith, Thomas, 1513-1577 (Box 182, Folder 3101)
    - Smith, Thomas, 1558?-1625 (Box 182, Folder 3102)
    - Smith, W. H. (William Henry), 1825-1891 (Box 182, Folder 3103)
    - Smith, W. Sidney (William Sidney), Sir, 1764-1840 (Box 182, Folder 3104)
    - Smollett, T. (Tobias), 1721-1771 (Box 182, Folder 3105)
    - Soane, John, 1753-1837 (Box 182, Folder 3106)
    - Somers, John Somers, Baron, 1651-1716 (Box 182, Folder 3107)
    - Somerset (Box 182, Folder 3108)
    - Somerset, Edward Seymour, Duke of, 1506?-1552 (Box 182, Folder 3109)
    - Somerville, William, 1675-1742 (Box 182, Folder 3110)
    - Sontag, Henriette, 1806-1854 (Box 182, Folder 3111)
    - Sorel, Agnès, ca. 1422-1450 (Box 182, Folder 3112)
    - Soult, Nicolas-Jean de Dieu, 1769-1851 (Box 182, Folder 3113)
    - Southampton (Box 182, Folder 3114)
    - Southey, Robert, 1774-1843 (Box 182, Folder 3115)
    - Spencer (Box 182, Folder 3116)
    - Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903 (Box 182, Folder 3117)
    - Spencer, John Charles Spencer, Earl, 1782-1845 (Box 182, Folder 3118)
    - Spenser, Edmund, 1552?-1599 (Box 182, Folder 3119)
    - Spinola, Ambrogio, 1569-1630 (Box 182, Folder 3120)
    - St. Albans, Harriot Mellon, Duchess of, 1777?-1837 (Box 183, Folder 3121)
    - St. Vincent, John Jervis, Viscount, 1735-1823 (Box 183, Folder 3122)
    - Staël, Madame de (Anne-Louise-Germaine), 1766-1817 (Box 183, Folder 3123)
    - Stanhope, James Stanhope, Earl, 1673-1721 (Box 183, Folder 3124)
    - Stein, Karl, Freiherr vom und zum, 1757-1831 (Box 183, Folder 3125)
    - Stephens, Alexander H. (Alexander Hamilton), 1812-1883 (Box 183, Folder 3126)
    - Stepney, George, 1663-1707 (Box 183, Folder 3127)
    - Sterne, Laurence, 1713-1768 (Box 183, Folder 3128)
    - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894 (Box 183, Folder 3129)
    - Stirling, William Alexander, Earl of, 1567 or 8-1640 (Box 183, Folder 3130)
    - Strafford, Thomas Wentworth, Earl of, 1593-1641 (Box 183, Folder 3131)
    - Struensee, Johann Friedrich, greve, 1737-1772 (Box 183, Folder 3132)
    - Suchet, Louis-Gabriel, duc d'Albufera, 1770-1826 (Box 183, Folder 3133)
    - Suckling, John, Sir, 1609-1642 (Box 183, Folder 3134)
    - Sue, Eugène, 1804-1857 (Box 183, Folder 3135)
    - Suffren de Saint-Tropez, Pierre André de, 1729-1788 (Box 183, Folder 3136)
    - Sully, Maximilien de Béthune, duc de, 1559-1641 (Box 183, Folder 3137)
    - Sussex, Thomas Radcliffe, Earl of, ca. 1525-1583 (Box 183, Folder 3138)
    - Sutherland (Box 183, Folder 3139)
    - Sutton, Thomas, 1532-1611 (Box 183, Folder 3140)
    - Suvorov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, kni︠a︡z' Italiĭskiĭ, 1730-1800 (Box 183, Folder 3141)
    - Swedenborg, Emanuel, 1688-1772 (Box 183, Folder 3142)
    - Swift, Jonathan, 1667-1745 (Box 183, Folder 3143)
    - Sylvester, Josua, 1563-1618 (Box 183, Folder 3144)
    - Oversize
      - Sa - Sc general, 11 (Box 184 (Oversize), Folder 3145-3155)
      - Se - Sl general, 10 (Box 185 (Oversize), Folder 3156-3165)
      - Sm - Stanh general, 11 (Box 186 (Oversize), Folder 3166-3176)
      - Stanl - Sz general, 13 (Box 187 (Oversize), Folder 3177-3189)
      - Sackville - Seymour, 36 (Box 188 (Oversize), Folder 3190-3225)
      - Shaftsbury - Southampton, 24 (Box 189 (Oversize), Folder 3226-3249)
      - Southy - Sylvester, 28 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 3250-3277)
  - T
    - Ta - Ti general, 9 (Box 191, Folder 3278-3286)
    - To - Tz general, 9 (Box 192, Folder 3287-3295)
    - Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930 (Box 193, Folder 3296)
    - Talbot (Box 193, Folder 3297)
    - Talfourd, Thomas Noon, Sir, 1795-1854 (Box 193, Folder 3298)
    - Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Bénévent, 1754-1838 (Box 193, Folder 3299)
    - Tallien (Box 193, Folder 3300)
    - Talma, François Joseph, 1763-1826 (Box 193, Folder 3301)
    - Tarleton, Lieutenant-General (Banastre), 1754-1833 (Box 193, Folder 3302)
    - Tasso, Torquato, 1544-1595 (Box 193, Folder 3303)
    - Taylor (Box 193, Folder 3304)
    - Taylor, Jeremy, 1613-1667 (Box 193, Folder 3305)
    - Taylor, John, 1580-1653 (Box 193, Folder 3306)
    - Taylor, Zachary, 1784-1850 (Box 193, Folder 3307)
    - Téllez Girón, Pedro, duque de Osuna, 1574-1624 (Box 193, Folder 3308)
    - Temple, William, Sir, 1628-1699 (Box 193, Folder 3309)
    - Tenison, Thomas, 1636-1715 (Box 193, Folder 3310)
    - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892 (Box 193, Folder 3311)
    - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 (Box 193, Folder 3312)
    - Thiers, Adolphe, 1797-1877 (Box 193, Folder 3313)
    - Thomas (Box 193, Folder 3314)
    - Thomas, à Becket, Saint, 1118?-1170 (Box 193, Folder 3315)
    - Thompson (Box 193, Folder 3316)
    - Thomson (Box 194, Folder 3317)
    - Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824 (Box 194, Folder 3318)
    - Thomson, James, 1700-1748 (Box 194, Folder 3319)
    - Thoresby, Ralph, 1658-1725 (Box 194, Folder 3320)
    - Thou (Box 194, Folder 3321)
    - Thou, Jacques-Auguste de, 1553-1617 (Box 194, Folder 3322)
    - Thouret, 1746-1794 (Box 194, Folder 3323)
    - Thurloe, John, 1616-1668 (Box 194, Folder 3324)
    - Tilly, Jean T'Serclaes, Comte de, 1559-1632 (Box 194, Folder 3325)
    - Toiras, Jean du Caylar de Saint-Bonnet, marquis de, 1585-1636 (Box 194, Folder 3326)
    - Tollemache, Thomas, 1651?-1694 (Box 194, Folder 3327)
    - Tone, Theobald Wolfe, 1763-1798 (Box 194, Folder 3328)
    - Tooke, John Horne, 1736-1812 (Box 194, Folder 3329)
    - Toulouse, Louis-Alexandre de Bourbon, comte de, 1678-1737 (Box 194, Folder 3330)
    - Tourville, Anne-Hilarion de Cotentin, comte de, 1642-1701 (Box 194, Folder 3331)
    - Tradescant (Box 194, Folder 3332)
    - Trivulzio, Gian Giacomo, 1441-1518 (Box 194, Folder 3333)
    - Tromp, Cornelis, 1629-1691 (Box 194, Folder 3334)
    - Tromp, Maarten Harpertsz., 1598-1653 (Box 194, Folder 3335)
    - Truguet, Laurent Jean François, 1752-1839 (Box 194, Folder 3336)
    - Trumbull, Jonathan, 1710-1785 (Box 194, Folder 3337)
    - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889 (Box 194, Folder 3338)
    - Turenne, Henri de La Tour d'Auvergne, vicomte de, 1611-1675 (Box 194, Folder 3339)
    - Turgot, Anne-Robert-Jacques, baron de l'Aulne, 1727-1781 (Box 195, Folder 3340)
    - Turner (Box 195, Folder 3341)
    - Twain, Mark, 1835-1910 (Box 195, Folder 3342)
    - Tyler (Box 195, Folder 3343)
    - Tyndale, William, d. 1536 (Box 195, Folder 3344)
    - Oversize
      - Ta - Th general, 8 (Box 196 (Oversize), Folder 3345-3352)
      - Ti - Tz general, 11 (Box 197 (Oversize), Folder 3353-3363)
      - Taft - Thackeray, 17 (Box 198 (Oversize), Folder 3364-3380)
      - Thiers - Turgot, 21 (Box 199 (Oversize), Folder 3381-3401)
  - U
    - Ua - Uz general, 2 (Box 200 (Oversize), Folder 3402-3403)
    - Uhland, Ludwig, 1787-1862 (Box 200 (Oversize), Folder 3404)
    - Upcott, William, 1779-1845 (Box 200 (Oversize), Folder 3405)
    - Ussher, James, 1581-1656 (Box 200 (Oversize), Folder 3406)
  - V
    - Va - Vis general, 10 (Box 201, Folder 3407-3416)
    - Vit - Vz general, 3 (Box 202, Folder 3417-3419)
    - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862 (Box 203, Folder 3420)
    - Vanbrugh, John, 1664-1726 (Box 203, Folder 3421)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1794-1877 (Box 203, Folder 3422)
    - Vane, Henry, Sir, 1612?-1662 (Box 203, Folder 3423)
    - Vansittart, Nicholas, 1766-1851 (Box 203, Folder 3424)
    - Vauban, Sébastien Le Prestre de, 1633-1707 (Box 203, Folder 3425)
    - Vaux (Box 203, Folder 3426)
    - Vega, Lope de, 1562-1635 (Box 203, Folder 3427)
    - Vendôme (Box 203, Folder 3428)
    - Vendôme, Louis-Joseph, duc de, 1654-1712 (Box 203, Folder 3429)
    - Vere, Francis, Sir, 1560-1609 (Box 203, Folder 3430)
    - Vere of Tilbury, Horace Vere, Baron, 1565-1635 (Box 203, Folder 3431)
    - Vergennes, Charles Gravier, comte de, 1719-1787 (Box 203, Folder 3432)
    - Vergniaud, Pierre-Victurnien, 1753-1793 (Box 203, Folder 3433)
    - Vernon, Edward, 1684-1757 (Box 203, Folder 3434)
    - Verri (Box 203, Folder 3435)
    - Vettori, Pietro, 1499-1585 (Box 203, Folder 3436)
    - Vigny, Alfred de, 1797-1863 (Box 203, Folder 3437)
    - Villaret de Joyeuse, Louis-Thomas, d. 1812 (Box 203, Folder 3438)
    - Villars (Box 203, Folder 3439)
    - Villars, Claude Louis Hector, duc de, 1653-1734 (Box 203, Folder 3440)
    - Villeroi (Box 203, Folder 3441)
    - Villiers de L'Isle-Adam, Philippe, 1464-1534 (Box 203, Folder 3442)
    - Vincent de Paul, Saint, 1581-1660 (Box 203, Folder 3443)
    - Vittoria, Grand Duchess, consort of Ferdinando II, Grand-Duke of Tuscany, 1622-1694 (Box 203, Folder 3444)
    - Voiture, Monsieur de (Vincent), 1597-1648 (Box 203, Folder 3445)
    - Volney, C.-F. (Constantin-François), 1757-1820 (Box 203, Folder 3446)
    - Voltaire, 1694-1778 (Box 203, Folder 3447)
    - Oversize
      - Va - Vz general, 10 (Box 204 (Oversize), Folder 3448-3457)
      - Van Buren - Voltaire, 21 (Box 205 (Oversize), Folder 3458-3478)
  - W
    - Wa - Wind general, 9 (Box 206, Folder 3479-3487)
    - Winm - Wz general, 3 (Box 207, Folder 3488-3490)
    - Waite, Morrison R. (Morrison Remick), 1816-1888 (Box 207, Folder 3491)
    - Wallack (Box 207, Folder 3492)
    - Wallenstein, Albrecht Wenzel Eusebius von, Herzog von Friedland, 1583-1634 (Box 207, Folder 3493)
    - Waller, Edmund, 1606-1687 (Box 207, Folder 3494)
    - Waller, William, Sir, 1597?-1668 (Box 207, Folder 3495)
    - Walsingham, Francis, 1577-1647 (Box 207, Folder 3496)
    - Walton, Izaak, 1593-1683 (Box 207, Folder 3497)
    - Warren (Box 207, Folder 3498)
    - Washington, George, 1732-1799
      - Hart numbers 1 - 99 (Box 208, Folder 3499)
      - Hart number 60, Rosenthal trial proof set (Box 208, Folder 3500)
      - Hart numbers 100 - 359, 5 (Box 208, Folder 3501-3505)
      - Hart numbers 360 - 799, 6 (Box 209, Folder 3506-3511)
      - Hart numbers 800 - 899 (Box 210, Folder 3512)
      - Prints without Hart numbers (Box 210, Folder 3513)
      - Prints without Hart numbers: two sets of progressive proofs (Box 210, Folder 3514)
      - Lithographs (Box 210, Folder 3515)
      - Portrait, wash drawing, unsigned and undated (Box 210, Folder 3516)
      - Facsimiles and reproductions, 2 (Box 210, Folder 3517-3518)
      - Title pages of books with Washington portraits, 1800-1875 (Box 210, Folder 3519)
      - Printed ephemera from Washington inaugural centennial celebrations, New York, 1889 April-May (Box 210, Folder 3520)
        General note
        Contains invitation, banquet program, menu, seating chart, etc.
      - Printed ephemera related to Washington, 1894-1932 (Box 210, Folder 3521)
        Contains J. O. Wright & Co. brochure, invitations, programs, Grolier Club exhibition catalogue, prospectus for Hart volume, etc.
    - Washington, Martha, 1731-1802 (Box 210, Folder 3522)
    - Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796 (Box 211, Folder 3523)
    - Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852 (Box 211, Folder 3524)
    - Westminster (Box 211, Folder 3525)
    - Wheeler, William A. (William Almon), 1819-1887 (Box 211, Folder 3526)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892 (Box 211, Folder 3527)
    - Wieland, Christoph Martin, 1733-1813 (Box 211, Folder 3528)
    - Wilkes, John, 1725-1797 (Box 211, Folder 3529)
    - William Augustus, Prince, Duke of Cumberland, 1721-1765 (Box 211, Folder 3530)
    - Wilson (Box 211, Folder 3531)
    - Wolseley, Garnet Wolseley, Viscount, 1833-1913 (Box 211, Folder 3532)
    - Wolsey, Thomas, 1475?-1530 (Box 211, Folder 3533)
    - Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850 (Box 211, Folder 3534)
    - Woronzoff-Dashkoff, Catherine (Box 211, Folder 3535)
    - Wrede, Karl Philipp, Fürst von, 1767-1838 (Box 211, Folder 3536)
    - Wurmser, Dagobert Sigmund, graf von, 1724-1797 (Box 211, Folder 3537)
    - Wurttemberg (Box 211, Folder 3538)
    - Oversize
      - Wa - Wz general, 10 (Box 212 (Oversize), Folder 3539-3548)
      - Waite - Warren, 8 (Box 213 (Oversize), Folder 3549-3556)
      - Washington, George, 1732-1799
        - Hart numbers 1 - 298, 7 (Box 214 (Oversize), Folder 3557-3563)
        - Hart numbers 245 + 700 (by S. Arlent Edwards after Savage and Stuart) (Box 214 (Oversize), Folder 3564)
        - Hart number 299 (by W. H. W. Bicknell), 1898; 2 (Box 215 (Oversize), Folder 3565-3566)
          Includes bound set of trial proofs and prints as issued.
        - Hart numbers 300 - 699, 10 (Box 215 (Oversize), Folder 3567-3576)
        - Hart numbers 704 - 706 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3577)
        - Hart number 707 (by Dawson Dawson Watson) (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3578)
          Includes prospectus slip for the mezzotint and a 1904 brochure for Dawson-Watson's summer painting school, Woodstock, NY
        - Hart numbers 708 - 837, 3 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3579-3581)
        - Hart number 838 (by Charles B. Hall after Hodson), 1898 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3582)
          Includes a letter from the publisher, Charles H. Lawrence, and sets of numered and signed proofs.
        - Hart numbers 839 - 899 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3583)
        - Prints without Hart numbers, 2 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3584-3585)
        - Portraits by Frederick T. Stuart for J. O. Wright & Co., 1906 (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3586)
          The folder contains numbered artist's proofs signed by Stuart and Wright, an issue of the Rye (N.Y.) Courier containing an article about the print, and a trimmed copy of the commercially issued print.
        - Lithographs (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3587)
        - Tracings by Robert Fridenberg (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3588)
        - Facsimiles and reproductions (Box 216 (Oversize), Folder 3589)
      - Washington, Martha, 1731-1802 (Box 217 (Oversize), Folder 3590)
      - Wayne - Wurmser, 12 (Box 217 (Oversize), Folder 3591-3602)
  - X - Y - Z
    - X - Z general (Box 211, Folder 3603)
    - Zola, Émile, 1840-1902 (Box 211, Folder 3604)
    - Oversize
      - X - Z general (Box 217 (Oversize), Folder 3605)
      - Zola, Émile, 1840-1902 (Box 217 (Oversize), Folder 3606)
  - Portraits from Vanity Fair
    A discrete group of chromolithographed caricatures of notable figures from the late nineteenth and early twentieth century, which were published in Vanity Fair, a weekly magazine with social, literary and political content issued in London between 1868 and 1914. The portraits are filed in alphabetical order by surname.
    - A - H, 8 (Box 218 (Oversize), Folder 3607-3614)
    - I - Q, 6 (Box 219 (Oversize), Folder 3615-3620)
    - R - Z, 8 (Box 220 (Oversize), Folder 3621-3628)
  - European Monarchs
    Filed here are portraits of "any ruler or sovereign bearing the title of king, queen, emperor, empress, or the equivalent of one of these," as defined by the Oxford English Dictionary, who ruled in Europe. England and France are the countries most represented, followed by houses, such as Orange and Nassau. Included here too are members of the Bonaparte family as their titles extended to so many countries. Folders may also contain portraits of rulers' consorts, with the exception of some, such as Marie Antoinette, who received their own folders.
    As with other sitters in the collection, proper names were taken from the Library of Congress Name Authority File.
    - British Isles
      - England
        This section contains the Kings and Queens of England. The folders also contain the appropriate spouses, consorts, mistresses, and offspring (e.g., Henry VIII's folders also contain Anne Boleyn and Catherine of Aragon, etc.).
        Arrangement
        Organized in chronological order by period of rule.
        - Edwin, King of Northumbria, 585?-633 (Box 221, Folder 3629)
        - Egbert, King of England, 769 or 771-839 (Box 221, Folder 3630)
        - Alfred, King of England, 849-899 (Box 221, Folder 3631)
        - Canute I, King of England, 995?-1035 (Box 221, Folder 3632)
        - Edward, King of England, ca. 1003-1066 (Box 221, Folder 3633)
        - Stephen, King of England, 1097?-1154 (Box 221, Folder 3634)
        - Henry I, King of England, 1068-1135 (Box 221, Folder 3635)
        - Henry II, King of England, 1133-1189 (Box 221, Folder 3636)
        - Richard I, King of England, 1157-1199 (Box 221, Folder 3637)
        - John, King of England, 1167-1216 (Box 221, Folder 3638)
        - Henry III, King of England, 1207-1272 (Box 221, Folder 3639)
        - Edward I, King of England, 1239-1307 (Box 221, Folder 3640)
        - Edward II, King of England, 1284-1327 (Box 221, Folder 3641)
        - Edward III, King of England, 1312-1377 (Box 221, Folder 3642)
        - Edward, Prince of Wales, 1330-1376 (Box 221, Folder 3643)
        - Richard II, King of England, 1367-1400 (Box 222, Folder 3644)
        - Henry IV, King of England, 1367-1413 (Box 222, Folder 3645)
        - Henry V, King of England, 1387-1422 (Box 222, Folder 3646)
        - Henry VI, King of England, 1421-1471 (Box 222, Folder 3647)
        - Henry VII, King of England, 1457-1509 (Box 222, Folder 3647a)
        - Henry VIII, King of England, 1491-1547 (Box 222, Folder 3648)
        - Henry VIII - wives of (Box 222, Folder 3649)
        - Elizabeth I, Queen of England, 1533-1603 (Box 222, Folder 3650)
        - James I, King of England, 1566-1625, 2 (Box 223, Folder 3651-3652)
        - Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649, 3 (Box 223, Folder 3653-3655)
        - Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685 (Box 223, Folder 3656)
        - James II, King of England, 1633-1701 (Box 223, Folder 3657)
        - Mary II, Queen of England, 1662-1694 (Box 224, Folder 3658)
        - Anne, Queen of Great Britain, 1665-1714 (Box 224, Folder 3659)
        - George I, King of Great Britain, 1660-1727 (Box 224, Folder 3660)
        - George II, King of Great Britain, 1683-1760 (Box 224, Folder 3661)
        - George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820 (Box 224, Folder 3662)
        - George IV, King of Great Britain, 1762-1830, 2 (Box 224, Folder 3663-3664)
        - William IV, King of Great Britain, 1765-1837 (Box 224, Folder 3665)
        - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901 (Box 224, Folder 3666)
        - Oversize
          - Egbert - Henry III, 9 (Box 225 (Oversize), Folder 3667-3675)
          - Edward I - James I, 13 (Box 226 (Oversize), Folder 3676-3688)
          - Charles I - Victoria, 10 (Box 227 (Oversize), Folder 3689-3698)
      - Scotland
        - James I, King of Scotland, 1394-1437 (Box 228, Folder 3699)
        - James II, King of Scotland, 1430-1460 (Box 228, Folder 3700)
        - James III, King of Scotland, 1451-1488 (Box 228, Folder 3701)
        - James IV, King of Scotland, 1473-1513 (Box 228, Folder 3702)
        - James V, King of Scotland, 1512-1542 (Box 228, Folder 3703)
        - Mary, Queen of Scots, 1542-1587, 3 (Box 228, Folder 3704-3706)
        - Oversize
          - James I - Mary, 8 (Box 229 (Oversize), Folder 3707-3714)
    - France
      Organized in alphabetical order. Queens, consorts, and children are filed with Kings. Prints of queens without kings are filed independently.
      - Anne, of Brittany, Consort of Louis XII, King of France, 1476-1514 (Box 230, Folder 3715)
      - Caribert (all) (Box 230, Folder 3716)
      - Carloman, King of the Franks, d. 754 (Box 230, Folder 3717)
      - Catherine de Médicis, Queen, consort of Henry II, King of France, 1519-1589 (Box 230, Folder 3718)
      - Charles, le Gros, Emperor, 839-888 (Box 230, Folder 3719)
      - Charles II, King of France, 823-877 (Box 230, Folder 3720)
      - Charles III, King of France, 879-929 (Box 230, Folder 3721)